This is Fairy 01.
（ターニャ）こちらフェアリー01
Confirming declaration of 177.
（ターニャ）第177号の発令を了解
帝国に勝利を
Victory to the Empire.
Now, troops, our job is to find
さて諸君 我々の仕事は
帰還途中の捜索遊撃任務
and destroy any enemy
forces attempting to retreat.
敵を見つけたら
襲ってもよろしい程度の仕事だ
All you have to do is attack
the enemy if you find them.
If the land forces'
performance is any indicator,
地上軍の働きぶりからして
出番は少ないだろう
you won't have much to do.
そういえば帝都では
我々の司令部襲撃をたたえ―
Back at the capital...
For our attack on enemy command,
ぜひ おごらせてくれというヤツが
軍団単位でいるそうだ
enough people to form an army
corps want to buy us drinks.
I can guarantee you'll have
free drinks for life.
タダ酒を一生分飲めると
保証しておくぞ
That's fantastic!
（隊員）最高だ！
Which does me no good, since I don't
drink anything harder than coffee.
（ターニャ）困ったことに
私はコーヒー党だがな
The first large-scale
encirclement since Cannae...
（ターニャ）
カンネー以来の大規模包囲戦か
The Empire has created an unassailable,
golden monument in military history.
帝国軍は戦史に不滅の金字塔を
打ち立てたわけだ
Now that I think about it, being a
soldier who lives amidst combat
思えば 戦火に身を浸す
軍人という存在は―
can make you lose your mind at times.
時として常識を失いがちだが―
平和さえ戻ってくれば 全ては
日常によって置換されるはず
But once there's peace again,
everyday life will restore everything!
So just a bit more...
だから もう少し…
I need to be a little more patient.
もう少しの辛抱だ！
With this attack... Just a bit more...
この一撃で あとわずかで…
戦争を終わらせられる！
the war will be over!
（通信兵）
ラインコントロールより各隊
Rhine Control to all units.
Multiple magical signatures
detected in area 42.
エリア42に複数の魔導反応
Look out for long-range
optical sniping spells.
長距離観測狙撃術式に警戒せよ
Area 42 is the patch of ocean near us...
（ヴァイス）エリア42というと…
近くの海上ですが
ジョンブルどもが介入したと？
The John Bulls are getting involved?
I'm just part of operations,
so I can't confirm.
（通信兵）悪いが
一介の管制には判断しかねる
Copy that.
We'll assume bogey is a bandit.
了解 ボギーをバンデットと推定す
よう撃の許可を！
Requesting permission to engage.
Sending a security echelon now.
（通信兵）
直ちに警戒部隊を向かわせる
You're to maintain your distance
and stand by until they arrive.
距離を保ったまま
到着まで待機せよ
Fairy 01, unable to comply! If we
can get the drop on them—
フェアリー01 承服できない！
先制でき… あっ！
グランツ！
Grantz!
One enemy down.
（アンソン）１機 撃墜
We can't reach Republican Control.
（ジェフリー）
やはり 共和国管制との
コンタクトは取れません
We must get control of the
situation and gather information.
（ドレイク）
現状把握および情報収集だ
強く当たるぞ！
Hit 'em hard!
（ヴィーシャ）
だ… 大隊規模の魔導部隊を視認！
A b-battalion of mages!
Designating bogeys as bandits!
（ヴィーシャ）ボギーを
バンデットと断定！ はっ…
Disperse!
散開！
Turn and intercept!
反転だ！ 迎撃する！
（ケーニッヒ）し… しかし
たったこれだけの数では
B-But there aren't enough of us...
Since they've sighted us, they'll pursue.
捕捉された以上は追撃される
So it's better than having
those bayonets up our asses!
ケツを掘られるよりはマシだ！
Form up! We'll get closer!
編隊形成！ 距離を詰めるぞ！
Roger!
Enemy company is forming up.
（魔導師）
敵中隊が隊列を形成！
Speed 300. Approaching fast!
速度300で急速接近中！
So that's her...
あれが例の…
Yeah... The Devil of the Rhine.
（ドレイク）ああ
“ラインの悪魔”だ… うっ
Everyone, assault formation.
各位 突撃隊形！ 行くぞ！
Let's go!
（アンソン）主よ… 我に力を
Lord, grant me power.
Episode Eleven
Resistance
When will reinforcements arrive?
（ターニャ）増援の到着は？
They say another 600 seconds.
およそ 600とのこと
Enemy is company-sized!
Overwhelm them with numbers!
敵は中隊規模だ！ 数で押し切れ！
Use the altitude difference!
高度差をいかせ！
出ている頭をたたけ！
Strike where they're vulnerable!
９時方向だ！ 急速旋回！
Nine o'clock!
Circle at high speed!
Enemy units lost.
（ジェフリー）敵影ロスト！
（ドレイク）深追いするな！
Don't pursue too far!
ハァ…
（魔導師）ぐあっ！
（魔導師）り… 離脱します！
L-Leaving the battlefield.
Damn it!
（ドレイク）クソッ！
（ターニャ）フンッ
（ヴィーシャ）キャー！
（ターニャ）くっ…
Trench guns?!
トレンチガン？
条約違反だぞ 野蛮人め！
That's a treaty violation, you barbarians!
Damn it, they're persistent.
クソッ しつこい！
03, covering you.
03！ カバーします！
もらったあ！
You're mine!
ケーニッヒ！ ノイマン！
Koenig...
Neumann!
くっ ぐう…
Idiot! Calm down!
バカが！ 落ち着け！
Stop! That's stupid!
よせ うかつだ！
ヴァイス！
Weiss!
（ドレイク）術式展開！
Activate spells.
Lord, if the day comes when
I fly through the heavens,
主よ 天翔(あまかけ)る日 来たらば―
I shall approach thee!
我 御許(みもと)に近づかん！
（ヴァイス）な…
（ターニャ）どけっ！
Move!
クソッ！
Damn it.
Damn it!
クソッ
Major...
少佐殿…
（アンソン）くっ…
（ターニャ）えいっ！
はっ！
こ… この男 あの時の！
H-He's that guy from before.
It is the Lord's guidance.
（アンソン）主のお導きだ
存在Ｘ(エックス)… また貴様か！
Being X...
You again?!
クソッ 離せ！ 離せ！
Damn it!
Let me go... Let me go!
離せ… うっ ううっ…
Let me go.
離せ～！
Let me go!
グハッ！
E-Enemy visual confirmation.
（魔導師）
て… 敵影 目視で確認！
大隊規模の増援です！
Reinforcements at battalion strength!
We're out of time, huh?
チッ 時間切れか
（ジェフリー）せ… せめて
大佐殿の遺品だけでも
I-If we can recover
something of the colonel's...
（ドレイク）もう無理だ！
It's hopeless now.
少佐殿！
Major!
We were supposed to
have the upper hand.
勝ち戦のはずが
何とも情けないな
Pathetic, huh?
（ターニャ）ハァ…
All Imperial forces
engaged in the mission...
（通信兵）作戦参加中の
全帝国軍部隊に告ぐ
We will now move to cleanup operations.
これより 掃討戦に移行せよ
繰り返す
Repeat.
We will now move
to cleanup operations!
掃討戦に移行せよ！
ウフフッ
Troops, we'll return home victorious!
諸君 凱旋(がいせん)だ！
15 Days After the Surround and Destroy Operation
July 10, Unified Year 1925
Republican Capital Parisée
This morning, the Republican government
declared their capital undefended.
（ラジオ音声）
本日午前 共和国政府が―
首都の無防備都市宣言を
布告しました
Imperial Capital Berun, Zolka Cafeteria
This declaration means the withdrawal
of Republican forces from the capital
これにより 共和国軍の
防衛守備隊も首都を撤退
and a glorious victory for the Empire.
我が帝国軍は
輝かしい勝利を手にしました
For the Fatherland!
（男性）祖国に！ かんぱ～い！
Cheers!
My highest compliments to
Strategic HQ once again.
（財務官）
参謀本部には改めて―
Imperial Army High Council, Diplomatic Briefing
賛辞を
贈らせていただきたい
Your decisive battle plan was brilliant,
類いまれなる決戦計画
そして首都の制圧
and then you took their capital.
Even the court is calling
it a splendid effort.
実に見事だったと
宮中でも大いに評判だ
We merely did our duty.
（ゼートゥーア）
我々は義務を果たしただけです
現場が よく働いてくれました
The ground troops did a good job.
（官僚）
それにしても共和国の連中
The Republic was awfully willing
to give up their capital, though.
随分あっさりと
首都を手放しましたなあ
（ルーデルドルフ）
まったく こちらは拍子抜けでした
Indeed, I was caught a little off-guard.
よほど 街の美観を
損ねたくなかったのでしょうなあ
They must have really wanted to keep us
from damaging the city's aesthetics.
（外務官）それでは
All right,
戦後処理に向けての話し合いに
移らせていただきますが―
moving on to the
post-war dispensations...
Does the military have any thoughts?
軍としての ご意見は何か？
Our mission is simply to
defend the Fatherland.
（ゼートゥーア）我々の仕事は
あくまでも祖国防衛です
そちらの職務を尊重し
口を挟むつもりはありません
We respect your position and
have no intention of interfering.
Thank you for the consideration.
お気遣いありがとうございます
At present, the Foreign Affairs Bureau
今のところ外務省としては
共和国に対し―
plans to have the Republic
abandon, or perhaps hand over,
いくつかの植民地放棄
ないしは割譲を要求するつもりです
several of their overseas colonies.
おお 意外に手堅いですな
Oh, surprisingly fair.
Treating the overseas
colonies as de facto satrapies
さすがに
事実上の従属国扱いでは
とても現実的では
ありませんからねえ
wouldn't be realistic.
I see...
なるほど 勝利の美酒に
酔った勢いでは
You can't devise peace plans
when you're drunk on
the wine of victory, huh?
講和案の策定もできないわけですか
ハハハハ…
Imperial Capital Outskirts, Unnamed Church
（少年）フンッ バカが！
（ターニャ）ん？
Fool!
（少年）思い知ったか！
（少年）調子に乗んな！
Did you learn your lesson?
Don't get cocky.
（少年）何だよ！
（少年）まだ やんのか？
What?
You want to fight more?
I'll... I'll never forgive you!
（少年）絶対… 絶対許さねえ！
（少年）何だ こいつ…
（少年）やっちまえ！
What's his problem?
Get him!
（殴る音）
（少年たち）おら！
Imperial Capital Berun, 203rd Aerial Mage Battalion Quarters
Imperial Army Secures Massive Victory
The War Is Over
（ヴィーシャ）あれ… 少佐殿
（ターニャ）あ？
Oh? Major?
I thought you were off today.
（ヴィーシャ）
今日は休暇のはずでは？
I don't really have anything to do.
特に やることもないのでな
さすがは少佐殿ですね
それに比べて男どもは…
That's the major for you.
And compared to you, the men are...
They're having a barbecue
on a Republican beach.
共和国のビーチで
バーベキューだそうですよ？
もう！
Jeez...
Somewhere in the Republic, Unnamed Beach
All companies, give me a report.
（ヴァイス）
各中隊！ 状況報告！
All troops ready for combat!
総員 第一種戦闘配備済み！
Provisions are also in order.
兵站(へいたん)状況にも 問題なし！
（グランツ）ビールよし！
ワインよし！ 肉魚 全てよし！
Beer, check!
Wine, check!
Meat, fish... Check!
Sea, check!
（隊員たち）海 よーし！
Very well! Begin the operation, men!
（ヴァイス）
よろしい！ 諸君 行動開始！
To victory!
（２人）勝利に！
（グランツ）戦友に！
To our comrades!
祖国に！
To our Fatherland!
Cheers!
（隊員たち）かんぱ～い！
Even if they are on leave,
aren't they taking it a little far?
いくら休暇中とはいえ
浮かれすぎですよね
It's summer already, huh?
（ターニャ）もう夏か…
Well, the war's over, either way.
（ヴィーシャ）まあ どのみち
戦争は終わりでしょうけど
Supposedly, the Republican Navy is withdrawing.
共和国海軍も撤退中らしいですし
（ターニャ）海軍が撤退？
（ヴィーシャ）はい
The navy's withdrawing?
Yes.
Under General Du Lugo's authority,
共和国軍は 次官級の
ド･ルーゴ将軍名義で―
the Republican Army ordered the
navy to cease combat and move.
戦闘の休止と移動を
命令したそうです
It's only a matter of time
until the end of the war.
これで終戦も時間の問題ですね
少尉 本国は
“終戦”と言ったのか？
Lieutenant, did HQ say "end of the war"?
Not "an armistice" or "surrender"?
“停戦”でも“降伏”でもなく？
H-Huh?
あ… はい？
“停戦”ではなく“終戦”と
口にしたのかと聞いている
I'm asking if they said "end of the war,"
as opposed to an armistice.
（ヴィーシャ）
そ… そう言われてみれば―
Th-Thinking back, I believe
the word was "armistice"...
“停戦”と聞いたような…
（ターニャ）撤退の指揮は
ド･ルーゴ将軍名義と言ったな
You said the withdrawal order
came from General Du Lugo?
Yes.
（ヴィーシャ）はい
（ターニャ）共和国軍はどこへ？
Where is the Republican Army?
Brest Military Port, I think.
確か ブレスト軍港へと…
Republican Territory Malgeria
Damn it!
（ターニャ）クソッ！
Why didn't I notice?
なぜ気がつかなかった！
少佐殿？
Major?
Lieutenant, contact the engineers
and have them ready the V-1s.
（ターニャ）少尉 技術省に
連絡して Ｖ－１(ブイワン)を用意させろ
（ヴィーシャ）は？
（ターニャ）例のＶ－１だ！
The V-1s... Have everyone
recalled here by air at once.
即刻 全員を空路で呼び戻せ！
休暇取り消しだ！
Vacation is canceled!
Wh-What?
（ヴィーシャ）な… 何を…
We're attacking Brest Military Port.
（ターニャ）
ブレスト軍港を襲撃する
Prepare for full assault!
全力出撃用意だ！
Republic, Brest Military Port
Get the rest of the cargo loaded!
（共和国兵士）
他の積み荷も急げー！
How is Operation Ark going?
（ド･ルーゴ）
箱舟作戦の状況は？
The 3rd Armored Division has boarded.
（部下）
第３機甲師団の乗船は完了しました
A mixed brigade from the 7th Strategic
Mobile Corps is currently boarding.
現在 第７戦略機動軍団より
集成旅団が乗船中です
We've confirmed the safety
of the sea route, as well.
（部下）
海路の安全も確認されています
The Allied Kingdom's fleets are
keeping the Empire at bay.
連合王国海軍が帝国艦隊を
牽制(けんせい)してくれているので―
数日は稼げるかと
That will buy us a few days.
We leave in two hours.
（ド･ルーゴ）２時間後に出港だ
時間まで最大限の積み込みを行え
Load as much as you can
before time runs out.
Yes, sir!
We're fleeing, leaving behind
（ド･ルーゴ）守るべき国土―
the people and land we're
supposed to protect, huh?
守るべき人々を
置き去りにしての逃亡か
I can't think of a more humiliating job.
これほど屈辱的な仕事は
思い当たらんな
Imperial Army Western Command
Please, let me go... Whatever it takes!
（ターニャ）
行かせていただきたい！
何としても私に！ 私の部隊に！
Let my unit go!
Major Degurechaff, calm down.
（ハンス）デグレチャフ少佐
落ち着きたまえ 貴官らしくもない
This isn't like you.
（ターニャ）
連中は本土を捨てて―
They plan to abandon the mainland and let
their counterattacking force flee overseas!
反攻の勢力を
逃がすつもりなのです！
取り逃がせば
帝国の勝利が揺らぎます！
If we let them escape,
our victory will be threatened!
Their fleet is as good as defeated.
（ハンス）もはや敗残の艦隊だ
無為に兵力を消耗して
停戦をぶち壊すつもりか？
Do you intend to ruin the armistice
and waste our manpower?
The armistice isn't in effect yet.
まだ停戦は発効しておりません
それに 停戦など一時的なもの
まだ戦争は続いております！
And an armistice is only temporary.
The war isn't over yet!
ハァ…
（ターニャ）どうか出撃を！
今しかないのです！
Please let me go!
Now is our only chance!
This brief window will decide if
the Empire gains the whole world,
このわずかな時間で
帝国が世界の全てを手に入れるか
or loses everything!
その全てを失うかが決まるのです！
少佐！ いいかげんにしたまえ！
Major, enough!
（ターニャ）
どうか ご理解いただきたく
思うのであります
I beg you to understand...
that I have to do my job as a soldier.
小官は軍人として なすべきことを
なさねばならないのだと…
ならん
No.
You refuse to allow me, no matter what?
どうあっても
お許しいただけませんか？
（ハンス）くどい！
Enough!
Very well.
分かりました
I understand and will respect
the demands of the theater forces.
方面軍の要請は理解し
尊重いたします
What?
何？
If we don't act now,
（ターニャ）今 動かねば
後世の歴史家から―
future historians may call us lazy.
怠慢だと言われかねません
In accordance with the privileges
Strategic Command has given me,
参謀本部より頂いた権限により
強行偵察任務を独断専行いたします
I will engage in force
reconnaissance under my own authority.
（ハンス）な… 何を…
Wh-What?
I ask that you not intervene.
お手出し無用に願います
Imperial Army V-1 Concealment Facility
Major, wait...
（衛兵）
少佐殿！ お待ちください！
（衛兵）どうか ご再考を！
Please reconsider!
High Command requested that I test the V-1s.
（ターニャ）本国から
Ｖ－１のテスト要請は受けている
I'm merely doing as they ask.
それに従うまでだ
Lieutenant, are Weiss and
the others here yet?
少尉 ヴァイスたちはまだか
もう時間が…
There's no time—
参謀本部より特命です
Special orders from Strategic HQ.
全部隊へ… 最優先だと
"To all units. Top priority."
It's an armistice order!
（ヴィーシャ）停戦命令です！
（ターニャ）くっ…
The mission is canceled.
出撃の中止を
（ターニャ）くっ… チクショウ！
Damn it...
Just a little more.
あと少しだぞ！
あと… あとわずかで…
Just... Just a tiny bit more.
戦争を…
And the war...
Major...
少佐殿…
Since I'm a soldier,
軍人である以上 命令に背けば
銃殺も免れないわけか…
I could face a firing squad
for disobeying orders, huh?
くっ… クソッ！
Damn it!
クソッ クソッ クソッ
クソー！ ううっ…
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
我々は… 我々は
戦争を終わらせる機会を―
We...
We had a chance to end the war,
逃したんだぞ…
and we let it slip...